I'm always telling you that's the
problem. That is the problem.
Well if you don't believe
in God, Brandon,
then how do you explain
the creation of
the universe?
How do you explain
the creation of God?
- He's always existed.
- So has the universe.
Bullshit.
Why? Why is that harder to
accept than your God?
There is no way that intelligent life
could have formed so quickly
without some kind of
divine intervention.
Come on, Roger, now you can't honestly
count someone like Jim here as
intelligent life, can you?
That's good. I'm impressed, Brandon.
I mean, that's almost witty.
Almost.
I'm gonna get another drink.
Like father, like son, huh?
You just don't know
when to quit, do you?
- Michael, I'm waiting.
- Okay.
How does he do this?
Speak of the devil.
Don't. I've had enough religious
discussion for one night.
What?
- When did you guys get here?
- Just walked in, man.
What, are you leaving me out there
with Lyndon's, uh, law school chum?
- Sorry.
- Priorities, man.
Jack first, hello second.
Whatcha drinkin'?
Whatever's handy.
Look, Jim, everyone is
kind of fancy out there.
You sure we're not a
little under dressed?
No, man, I think they're
a little overdressed.
Alright.
Speaking of which, who's the guy
in the eight hundred dollar suit?
- He's Brandon Sinclair.
- Of the Sinclair Vineyards?
Mhm.
- Linda used to date him.
- I'm impressed.
So's he.
Jealous?
Jim? Hi, Lloyd. Hi, Mike.
Hi.
Well, I guess we'll go
rinse out some things.
Sorry. Excuse me.
Are you alright?
I told you he was an asshole.
I know you did.
You gonna come back
out to the party?
In a minute.
Look, can you just go
play hostess, you know?
Try to come up with
some clean jokes, okay?
Okay.
Jim.
I love you.
I know.
How can you believe in spirits if
you don't believe in God or Satan?
There's been evidence
of their existence.
Eyewitness accounts, photographs,
recordings, you name it.
And I've contacted some of them.
With what, a wee-gee board?
- Ouija.
- What?
It's pronounced, "Ouija,"
not "wee-gee."
It comes from the French and German
"Oui" and "Ja." Ouija.
And this is a planchette.
I don't care what you
call it, dude. It's just
like a game. Like checkers, or chess.
For your information,
"dude," the Ouija board
has been around since
recorded history.
It was in wide use as
far back as 540 B.C.
I guess if Barbie dolls
had been around
for that long you'd be
talking to them too.
Beats talking to you.
Well, that's because I use words
with more than one syllable.
Oh, would you like to talk about that?
- Yeah.
- Um, look, guys...
Can we play a bit of the
game? That would be fun.
Alright.
Now, for the best results,
the Ouija should
be used by two people,
preferably a man
and a woman. And it
shouldn't be sitting on
a table. It should sit
on our knees so that
there's as much body
contact as possible.
Also, the two people should
have clean, pure systems,
so that the energy flowing
from us to the
planchette is as strong as it can be.
Are you saying that the spirits
actually come through our bodies?
Oh, don't worry. It's perfectly safe.
I don't think I quite
understand what you
mean by a clean system, though.
Someone who doesn't
smoke or drink, like you.
Care to give it a try?
No, I don't think so...
Come on, come on. Jeez,
just give it a try. Come on!
- Alright.
- Alright, good. Alright!
Good. I don't smoke either, and
I haven't been drinking tonight.
So together, we should be able
to make a clear, strong contact.
I'll bet he wants a
clear, strong contact.
Alright, one more thing
before we begin.
The spirits are lousy spellers
and a lot of them like to lie.
So just to play it safe, I'm gonna
try to contact David.
The spirit of a little boy who
died about thirty years ago.
You mean you've actually
talked to this spirit before?
Yeah, I've contacted
him several times.
For some reason he is connected
to this particular board.
Why's that?
Well, I don't know, really.
It's just that every Ouija
board seems to have
its own dominant spirit.
Maybe it's because this board
was made the day David died.
How do you know when
that board was made?
David told me.
How do you know he
wasn't lying. You said
they liked to lie.
Didn't you say that?
Uh, I'd really like to try this.
Alright.
David. Are you here?
Can you hear me?
- Can I talk to him?
- Yeah, go ahead.
How old are you, David?
Uh, thank you very
much. Goodbye.
- Why did you stop?
- Oh, that wasn't David.
- Well then who was it?
- I don't know.
Like I said, they like
to lie sometimes.
Well, David was ten when
he died, not eight.
Besides, we have a special signal
that no other spirit knows.
Ooh. That's a little spooky.
- It's a little stupid.
- It's a lot stupid.
David, can you hear me?
Would you like to talk to us?
David, is that you?
- It's doing a figure eight.
- That's David's signal.
Would you like to speak to him?
Yeah, I would.
David?
I don't know what to say to him.
David. Do you know me?
David, will you return
to the living one day?
- Reincarnation?
- That's what they all say.
David.
Will you be able to choose your
parents when you return?
Bullshit.
What? You can't believe
you were stupid
enough to pick your parents?
Hey, I don't talk to cardboard.
- Careful, Jim, you're upsetting David.
- What's he gonna do, haunt me?
David, are you all right?
He's alright. He's just
a little dead, that's all.
Shut up, Jim! David,
are you all right?
Brandon, it's really racing.
Yeah, maybe he's late for the
last flight back to limbo.
- What was that noise?
- Sounded like a gunshot.
'Scuse me, folks. Pardon me.
Oh, man, multiple sadness.
Who owns the red Cobra?
- I do, why?
- Your tires are history, bud.
Thanks a lot, Morar.
- What? This is my fault?
- Those were brand new tires!
Now how do you explain it?
I don't know man, maybe
your buddy Casper did it.
That's right. Because
you made him angry.
Then why didn't he
flatten my tires?
Why? Because I was in control of
the board; he held me responsible.
- You're crazy.
- You're drunk.
And you're a loser. In
a great family tradition.
Jim! Jim.
Well thank you very much
for ruining the party.
You're welcome.
But don't worry.
The night's still young.
Are you serious?
Look at me. I am furious
with you right now.
I know. And you're so gorgeous
when you're angry.
Look. Don't joke when
you're this close to death.
Okay, okay. I'm sorry about the
party and I'm sorry about Brandon.
And I'm sorry about the
crisis in the Middle East.
Alright. That's it.
Come on, come on. You knew you were
taking a chance when you invited him.
I know your heart was in the right
place. It just didn't work out.
Jim, you promised me that you weren't
gonna start anything with him.
I kept my promise.
He started it.
What did you want me to do?
Just sit there and take it?
No, I guess not.
I really am sorry.
I know.
- Why do I love you so much?
- 'Cause I make you laugh.
Yeah? And Woody Allen makes me laugh.
I know, but I'm sexier.
Whatcha doing?
I lost my hammer.
Use mine.
Sucker, you could have killed me.
Nah, then you'd come back and haunt
me and flatten my tires and stuff.
Sit down, sit down.
Linda's putting Twinkies
in my lunch again.
Ms. Brewster, this is
Dr. Gelineau's office
calling. We have the
results of your test
back from the lab. You can
call us today until 12:30.
Hello, Linda. This is
Brandon. I just realized
I left my Ouija here
the other night.
Could you bring it to class
this Friday? I'm having
some friends over Sunday
and they want to use it.
Besides, I want to contact David
to see if he's calmed
down yet. Well, see you Friday. Bye.
David, are you here?
David, is that you?
David, do you remember me?
David, is it true that you can really
choose your next parents?
Do you know why I'm asking?
The tests... They're positive.
David, would you like to-
No? How come?
J. I. M.
Jim? What? You don't like Jim?
Well, Jim's a really nice g-
Boy, David, you sure know how
to hold a grudge, don't you?
David? David, are you here?
David, where are you?
Man, don't tell me you bought that
crap with Brandon and that board.
Oh, please. What do you-Do you see
"Spaz" written on this man anywhere?
Please.
So how'd the board
jump off their knees?
I dunno, man. He probably kicked it.
He always was about as clever
as a bag full of doorknobs.
What is it with you guys, anyway?
Linda, I guess. At least that's
when the friendship ended.
You guys were friends?
Best friends.
When we were kids.
Get outta here.
Yeah, I practically grew
up in Brandon's house.
Both my folks were
alcoholics, and, uh...
I didn't want to spend too
much time at home.
He thinks I stole Linda from him.
- Did you?
- No.
No.
I didn't even know they
knew each other.
I'd been off at med school, and when I
met her they'd already broken up.
You went to med school?
Didn't know I was such a
multifaceted dude, did you?
I didn't know you had more
than one brain cell, James.
What are you doing here?
Love. Come on, lunch is over.
No! Daddy, please?
Come on, I want to finish
the job this month.
You are bringing me way down, bud.
You're a lazy scumbag, you know that.
Employment means
nothing to me, pal.
Lloyd?
David, are you here?
Well, it's nice to see
you made it back.
R.
I.
N.
G.
Ring?
My diamond ring?
You know where it is?
Where?
D.
R.
A.
N.
You mean "drain?"
Like a sink drain?
Which sink? The kitchen?
The bathroom.
Thanks, David.
Oh! Ow. Darn.
There goes my nail.
Jesus Christ, don't ever sneak
up on me again. Fuck!
Shit.
Fuck.
What are you doing home?
I live here.
What are you up to?
I found my ring. Remember the one
that I lost when we moved in? See?
And that's such a monumental event
that you started swearing?
What?
Your language, babe. I think
"gosh" and "darn" are
the strongest words I've
ever heard you use.
And when did you take up plumbing?
You're never gonna believe
this. David, he told-
Uh, David who?
You remember David. The
spirit of the little boy?
Oh, I don't need to
hear this shit now.
Jim! What's-What's the matter?
They closed the site early today.
There was an accident, and...
Lloyd, uh...
Lloyd got killed.
Oh, god, what happened?
There was a load of sheet rock, and it
wasn't secured properly,
and it... fell.
I've never liked you doing
that job. It is so dangerous.
Everything is dangerous.
Mr. Morar?
My name is Duherst.
Lieutenant Duherst.
- Police?
- Homicide.
I didn't know Fairfield had
a homicide division.
I'm it! I'm also the bomb squad
and the truancy division.
- Do you like magic?
- What?
Magic, you know. Card tricks, sawing
ladies in half. Magic.
Yeah, I guess.
Me too. I always wanted
to be a magician.
I don't have the hands for it, though.
Not, uh, dextrous enough.
- Then how do you defuse bombs?
- I don't know.
No one's ever planted a bomb here.
What can I do for you, lieutenant?
I'm investigating Mr.
Salvador's death.
You ever been to Vegas?
No. Why?
They got these two guys
there, Sigmund and Roy.
I mean, they are the best
magicians I have ever
seen, without a doubt.
I mean, they do some
really amazing things.
You know, there's only
one thing I like better
than seeing a good magic trick.
It's trying to figure
out how it was done.
Lieutenant, we're not really talking
about magic, here, are we?
No.
I believe Mr. Salvador was murdered.
The ropes holding the sheet
rock on the scaffolding
were cut, apparently with
some sort of hatchet.
- Are you sure?
- I'm afraid so.
Did he have any enemies?
No. None that I know of.
I understand that you were with him
when the sheet rock fell.
Now, is there any
chance that the killer
could have been aiming for you?
- I don't think so.
- Are there any other witnesses?
No. No, I'm afraid not.
And you lost your hatchet
that same day.
I lost my hammer.
But it has a blade on one side, right?
Have you found it yet?
No. No, I had to buy a new one.
Just vanished into thin air, huh?
Nothing up my sleeve.
Touche.
I'm sorry for intruding here.
Jim, you didn't tell me
you were with him.
I didn't think it was important.
It is important, it could
have been you!
Hey, it was just an accident, that's
all. It was just an accident.
Can we go?
Well, the lieutenant's
not too sure about that.
And neither am I.
David? Did you cause that
accident at the site?
David, don't lie to me.
Are you still angry at Jim?
David?
David.
Hello?
Where were you?
What?
You were supposed to bring
my Ouija by class yesterday.
God, I am so sorry,
I completely forgot.
I went to the funeral with Jim.
Oh. Yeah, of course, uh...
Well, how's he taking it?
Well, he's sleeping right now.
Kind of figures.
Brandon, that's not even fair.
Isn't it? Tell me, did he
cry at the funeral?
Face it, Linda.
The man has ice in his
veins. I've known him
since he was seven and I've
never seen him cry once.
Not once. Not for anybody or anything.
Brandon? How many times
have you contacted David?
David?
Quite a few times. Why?
Have you ever seen him get that angry?
No, never. Look, did we just change
subjects when I wasn't looking?
Brandon, I've been getting a little
worried. I've been using the Ouija.
Alone?
Yeah. Why?
Linda, listen to me.
Hello? Hello?
Brandon?
- Hello?
- Hello.
God damn it, how many times have
I told you not to sneak up on me?
Look, I'm sorry, next
time I'll wear a bell.
Why don't you just rattle your
fucking head next time?
What the hell's eating you?
I don't know.
I don't know, I'm so scared.
I feel like I'm going crazy.
It's alright.
It's gonna be alright.
I'm pregnant.
Are you sure?
I mean, did you see a doctor?
I already know.
I have an appointment on Monday.
And I've been having morning
sickness all week.
Well, no wonder.
No wonder you're a nervous wreck.
You're not going crazy. You're
just becoming a mother.
Granted, it's almost the same thing.
You're not upset?
No. No. Of course not.
God, I love you.
I know.
And you love me.
Even though you don't
know it, I know it.
I'm giving the board back
to Brandon today.
I've already made up my mind, David.
There's nothing you can do about it.
Oh my god.
Hey. Hey. Do you know
Jim Morar? Where is he?
What are you doing here?
I tried to call but your
phone was dead.
And you drove all the way
out here to tell me that?
No. I want to ask you
something about Linda.
You want to know if she snores.
I should've known better.
Hey. Hey! Jesus, man, you used
to have a sense of humor.
Okay, can you be serious
for one minute, please?
I'll give it a shot.
Has Linda been acting
strange lately?
She hasn't been to a single
one of her classes all week.
What do you mean, "strange?"
I mean nervous tension,
insomnia, nausea,
any kind of erratic behavior?
How did you know?
Has she been swearing a lot?
Like a truck driver.
I think Linda's been using my Ouija.
No.
Alright. Alright, I know you
think this is a crock of shit.
But just bear with me
for a minute, please.
Okay.
Okay. When someone
uses a Ouija alone,
like Linda, she's very
susceptible to the
spirits she contacts. And the wrong
spirit will take advantage of this.
At first, he'll be extremely
helpful and friendly.
So that she's lured into using
the board more and more.
Pretty soon all she wants
to do is use the board.
Everything else, like going to
classes, becomes unimportant.
This is called progressive entrapment.
When she reaches this
stage, the spirit changes.
He starts to frighten
and terrorize her.
Gradually breaking down
her resistance. And
once that's done, he's
able to possess her.
So, what you're telling me is
that I'm living with Linda Blair.
Dammit, Jim, I'm serious!
I know. That's what makes it so funny.
I thought you were an atheist, man.
Look, I'm not saying
that it's a demon.
Just the spirit of someone evil.
Evil when he was alive and
evil now that he's dead
I want to bring a medium
by your apartment
as soon as possible
to exorcise the spirit.
You're serious.
Jim.
How do you think I knew all
those things about Linda?
Those are all symptoms of
progressive entrapment.
They're also all symptoms
of pregnancy.
What?
Linda's pregnant.
I'm going to be a father.
Terrific.
Come on, Brandon. I mean,
can't you be happy for us?
You gonna marry her?
Yeah.
Of course.
You don't even love her.
Let me tell you something. You
haven't talked to me in two years.
So don't stand there
and tell me how I feel.
I know you better than
you think I do, Jim.
I knew why you dropped out
of med school, does Linda?
Because you knew you'd
make a lousy doctor.
Because you're not capable of giving
a shit about anyone but yourself.
Shut up, Brandon.
And when you get tired
of Linda you're gonna
walk away from her too,
just like with school.
Shut up, Brandon.
Just like you did with your
parents, just like with-
Shut up!
- Jim?
- What?
There's a phone call for you
in the foreman's trailer.
- Take a message, I'm busy.
- It's your landlady, man.
It's something about Linda.
She alright?
Hello?
Jim, this is Mrs. Boses.
Is Linda alright?
Well, she's fine now but she
was scared awfully bad.
Well, let me talk to
her. Is she there?
Yeah. Just a minute.
- Jim?
- I'm right here, babe.
- It was David.
- David?
Yeah.
Jim, he used to be so nice, but-
I don't know, I'm just so scared.
It's alright, babe. I'm
on my way home.
And I'll take care of it, I promise.
Alright?
Okay.
Alright, bring your medium by tonight.
Jim, this is Zarabeth. Best
medium in Northern California.
Hi. Thanks for coming.
No prob, heh. Hey, nice place.
But, uh, you got yourself one gnarly
spirit here, I can feel it.
- See the hair standing up on my arm?
- Mhm.
This is your expert? Where'd
you find her, the circus?
- OK, she's a bit strange, but...
- A bit strange?
Her head looks like
a friggin' rainbow.
You must be Linda.
- Uh, Linda, this is Zarabeth.
- Hi.
She's a medium.
How bitchin'.
Uh, yeah, I prepared everything
like he said to.
Top-notch job, Jim. Let's get
this show on the road.
I can't believe you did all
this while I was sleeping.
Okay.
I'm gonna make contact now, so
whatever happens, stay in your seat.
Alright? If you stand or talk,
the contact might be broken.
Oh.
Bummer.
I forgot my crystal ball. Ha!
Just a little psychic humor, I don't
really have a crystal ball.
Should we hold hands
or something?
Nah, that's just in the
vampire movies.
Anyway, my nails are too grody.
Okay, let's talk to some ghosts.
Who are you?
Please don't hate me.
David.
David, do you know me?
Yes, Brandon, I know you.
How old are you?
Ten.
I passed away.
Tell us. Why are you
terrorizing Linda?
I love Linda.
Then why are you frightening her?
She hurt me. She won't
talk to me anymore.
Because of him.
Jim?
He is cruel.
You are cruel, David.
Linda fears you.
I'm sorry.
I was angry.
I...
I love you.
Linda no longer wishes
to speak to you.
I am taking the Ouija
home with me tonight.
I know.
The woman you are speaking
through is a psychic.
She has the power to exorcise
you from this apartment.
No... I'll go.
I never meant to harm anyone.
Goodbye.
- David, why...
- Goodbye.
- David, wait!
- Linda! Don't!
Ahh.
Brandy, catch the lights, huh?
Huh?
Oh, yeah.
Zarabeth, thank you.
Too cool.
But I didn't do it. David
left on his own.
Yeah, well, he sure knows how
to make a dramatic exit.
Well, maybe I reacted
a little too quick.
What?
I don't know, maybe I should
have given him more
of a chance, you know?
He's not evil, he's just...
He's just like a little boy.
No way.
No way. He is taking this thing
home now. And that's it.
Believe me, Linda, we
did the right thing.
Oh, for sure.
I mean, that was one nasty ghost.
Good thing the exorcism didn't happen.
It would have been mondo tough.
I see a vision.
What is it?
Me... Ln your car...
Going home.
Just some more psychic humor.
Come on, Brandy, let's
hit the musty dusty.
T.T.F.N.
"T.T.F.N.?"
Uh, "ta ta for now."
Uh, thanks for letting me bring her.
Don't mention it. To anybody.
You did a good job tonight. Thank you.
You ever heard of the
word "Malfeitor" before?
Malfeitor? It's Portuguese,
it means someone evil.
Why?
Was David Portuguese?
No, I don't think so.
And he's only ten years old?
Yeah.
Whoa. He must have taken some mega
vitamins, 'cause he
was a real toughie.
Something's bothering
you. What is it?
I see danger ahead.
- For Linda?
- For you, if you miss my house.
It's coming up on the right.
A little more psychic humor, huh?
All kidding aside, though,
something is really icky.
Like what?
Not sure. Stay by the phone and
I'll call you later on tonight
after I do the Nancy Drew bit.
T.T.F.N.
♪ In the middle of the summer ♪
♪ In the middle of the night ♪
♪ She was deaf from her own heartbeat ♪
♪ Still she heard something move ♪
♪ It was just out of sight ♪
♪ and the morning was way out of reach ♪
♪ Well she's made the answer ♪
♪ By the light of the day ♪
♪ Oh it's so far away ♪
You!
Police are calling it
the worst traffic
accident in the county's history.
An accident of a different
sort claimed the
life of a Fairfield woman
late last night
when she fell to her death from
a second-floor window.
The woman, Sarah
Crawford, claimed to be
a psychic and worked as a professional
medium under the
pseudonym of "Zarabeth."
Police officials will
not divulge whether
the death was suicide or murder, but
a full-scale investigation is
presently underway.
Thank you, Stu. Lee'll be back
with weather right after this.
Yeah, who is it?
Jim, it's Brandon. We have to talk.
Alright, I'll buzz you up.
Okay, but meet me
in the upstairs lobby.
- What's up?
- Where's Linda?
She's asleep, man. Why?
Come here.
Zarabeth is dead.
What?
Someone or something
pushed her out a window.
Jesus Christ.
She suspected something
about David, she was
going to check on it. I
think David killed her.
Wait a minute, man.
The spirit killed her?
Yes, and I think he cut the
phone line too, so I
couldn't warn Linda about
the Ouija, and he
probably killed Lloyd.
But that time I think
he was after you.
Man, are you listening to yourself?
You're telling me there's
a ten-year-old ghost
flying around Fairfield
killing people.
Look.
I know it sounds crazy but
I am sure that I'm right.
I mean, assuming that you are,
why would he wait until now?
You contacted him long before Linda.
I've never been alone. I've always had
people with me when I use the Ouija.
OK, so you took it home.
No. I checked the box this
morning. No Ouija.
Man, that's impossible,
I boxed it myself.
Well, maybe Linda removed
it when you weren't
looking. She's obsessed with it, Jim!
That means that she's already fallen
into progressive entrapment.
Well, then I just have to find the
damn thing and get rid of it.
It's too late for that.
Linda is so open now,
I don't think David needs it anymore.
You told me that that's where
he got his power.
It's just a portal. Most
spirits are trapped in their
world and can't enter ours
without some kind of
help, like a medium or a Ouija.
Or someone that's been opened
by progressive entrapment.
Yes.
You're telling me that Linda
is a portal for David.
Eventually.
He'll possess her, unless
we can stop him.
That's why I'm going to Big Bear.
What's in Big Bear?
That's where David claims he died.
Now I have to go there and
check out his story.
We can't fight unless we know exactly
who he is and how powerful he is.
For all I know, he's been lying to me
since the first time I contacted him.
You're really going up there?
I have to.
I feel responsible.
Wait, you gonna leave now?
Yeah, until I get back, you
keep an eye on Linda.
Brandon.
Listen, man.
Look, I don't know-I don't
know if I buy all this.
But good luck.
David, are you here?
David, have you come back?
Jim!
Jim, help!
Linda?
Open up. Open the door.
Jim!
Linda, unlock the door!
Jesus.
Jim? Linda?
Is everything alright?
Hello? Jim? Linda?
Mrs. Moses, call an ambulance.
Why, what happened?
Linda's hurt.
She's unconscious.
Doctor Rogers, 1742.
Duherst, what do you want from me?
You know, I don't think I've got the
dexterity to be a juggler either.
My, my, that was rude.
I got a D in manners.
How well did you know Sarah
Crawford, aka Zarabeth?
- Why, was she into card tricks?
- I don't know.
But she managed to get her throat slit
before she went through a window.
That's a pretty neat trick
in anybody's book.
What do you think her
throat was slit with?
A hatchet?
Whatever it was, her throat
matched the ropes
that were cut on
the construction site.
Have you found your hammer yet?
No. I guess it just vanished.
You know, I saw this magician
once. He managed
to make an entire
elephant disappear.
An entire elephant!
That's no mean feat, either.
Just a tiny elephant's pretty tough
just to stick up your sleeve.
Of course, I know that
he didn't really
make that elephant
vanish into thin air.
He just managed to hide it someplace.
- Mr. Morar?
- Yes?
I'm Dr. Gelineau.
Is Linda alright?
Your diagnosis was right
on the nose, a mild
concussion. That must
have been quite a fall.
Yeah.
How's the baby?
Linda missed her appointment
yesterday, so I didn't
get a chance to tell her,
but she's not pregnant.
But she's had morning
sickness all week...
Nevertheless.
I'm sorry.
Can I see her?
Sure, but she's still unconscious.
I'm going with you.
What's our first move
when we get there?
Big Bear Public Library.
Why?
Why not?
Well, as long as you've
got a reason.
Oh. Hello.
What?
Wait a minute. Let me enlarge it.
Bingo.
A gasoline explosion aboard
a small motorboat claimed
the life often-year-old David Simpson
early yesterday morning.
Funeral services for David, the only
child of John and Betty Simpson,
will be held this Saturday at the
Green Meadows Cemetery.
Well, now we know David's
telling the truth.
We still don't know why
he's terrorizing Linda.
How do we find that out?
We ask his parents.
Damn it! There's not one listing
for John or Betty Simpson.
Did the article say David was buried
at the Green Meadows Cemetery?
Yeah. So?
So maybe the caretaker's got
their address on an invoice.
Jesus, don't do that to me, alright?
Sorry, man.
Look, nobody's home.
Place is locked up.
Oh, damn it.
I guess we're just gonna have
to come back tomorrow.
Well, as long as we're here, I'm
gonna check out David's grave.
Why?
Why not?
No, Jim, don't!
I've got a very bad
feeling about this.
Oh, god, I've got a bad
Jim?
Where are you?
Whoa!
Shit.
Oh, god.
You scared the shit out of me.
Shut up, just shut up.
You're gonna get
us both arrested for grave robbery.
Where were you?
I found someone I want you to meet.
Who?
David's parents.
Look at the date, man.
David's parents died on the same day.
Less than two weeks ago.
Must have been some
kind of an accident.
What if it wasn't?
I'm going to
try and get some sleep.
Gotta get out to the dock
first thing in the morning.
I don't suppose you have an
extra toothbrush in that bag.
I'm afraid not.
Damn, I hate talking to ghosts
with plaque on my teeth.
A little psychic humor.
God, why are we laughing?
It helps us forget how scared we are.
What happened to us, man?
We used to be like brothers.
I don't know. Things change.
People change.
I didn't steal her from
you. You know that.
I know.
It's just that every time I see the
two of you together, I go crazy.
I start saying stupid
things and I can't stop.
I tell myself, "Brandon, stop
being such an asshole."
Then my mouth pops open and
out comes another stupid quip.
You're still in love with her.
I envy you that.
You remember what you said
about me quitting med school?
Jim, I'm sorry, I didn't mean that.
No, no, you were right.
You know what I'm afraid of
more than anything else?
That I'll never be able
to love anyone.
And that I'm gonna end up spending
the rest of my life alone.
If I had any real guts
I'd get out of her life
before she wastes any more time on me.
So tell me.
What does she see in you
that she didn't see in me?
I make her laugh.
So did I.
Yeah. But only in the bedroom.
You really are an asshole,
you know that?
Yeah.
Linda.
Linda. Come here.
- What'd you get?
- Take it.
Let's go.
Oh, man.
- Haven't we seen enough of these?
- We're gonna need it to contact David.
Man, I got a real bad
feeling about this.
What are you doing, man? I thought
we had to put this thing on our knees.
Not this time.
Since this is where
David died, contact
with the spirit should be very strong.
Not too strong, I hope.
Don't worry. If I'm right
about Linda being his
portal, she's too far away
for him to reach us.
What if you're wrong and
the Ouija's the portal?
We're gonna be opening the
door if we use this thing.
I'm not wrong.
Linda is his portal. David can't hurt
us here, we're too far away.
Besides, he can't do anything
while she's sleeping.
She's under sedation, right?
Yeah.
Linda?
I think you should stay and let
us run some more tests.
Oh, no, I feel fine. I just
want to go home now.
Thanks.
David, why are you terrorizing Linda?
"N-O?" N-O-what?
"T."
"N-O-T." Not?
David, do you mean you're
not terrorizing Linda?
Then who is?
Evil. What the hell
does that mean?
I don't know.
Wait a minute.
David. You were at Jim's
party, weren't you?
And you flattened my tire?
David, now, this is very important.
Please tell us the truth.
Did you kill Lloyd at
the construction site?
And you didn't kill Zarabeth?
But you did speak to
us through her.
No.
Then who the hell did we talk to?
Again with the evil.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
I think I have it.
David.
Is this evil another spirit?
Is this spirit powerful? Did it force
you out of Jim's apartment?
Is this spirit's name Malfeitor?
Then Linda never actually
contacted you
all the time she was using my Ouija.
Alright, then who's Malfeitor?
That's what we're gonna find out.
David? Who is Malfeitor?
"Her?" Who is "her?"
David, do you mean Linda?
Well, then who is "her?"
What's wrong?
I don't know, he's agitated.
Be careful.
David, are you alright?
What's the matter?
Hey.
Didn't you say they
were lousy spellers?
David, did you misspell the word?
Alright. Okay.
Just try again.
One more time, slowly.
Who is Malfeitor?
H.
E.
R.
What happened?
I lost him.
It happens sometimes. David.
- Can't you get him back?
- I don't know! David!
- What is he trying to spell here?
- I don't know! David?
H-E-R-E. Here!
Malfeitor is here.
But he can't be, that would mean...
Jim.
Brandon?
Brandon!
Oh! Jesus!
Oh, god.
Oh. Oh, god.
David?
David, where are you?
David, what have you done with Jim?
David, answer me, goddammit.
Bastard.
Carlos Malfeitor was
a fairly notorious
mass murderer in his day.
He killed nine people. Chopped
them all up with an axe.
Whatever happened to him?
Is he still alive?
No, the police finally caught
up to him around 1930.
Shot him down in his own home.
There it is.
Hello?
Yes, I'd like to speak
to Linda Brewster.
She's a patient in room 310.
No! No. 375.
It's an emergency!
What? When?
Linda?
Jesus Christ.
Linda, I'm trying to help you.
Fine. Then stop moving.
Go ahead, James.
What are you waiting for?
Linda...
I love you.
Jim?
God, Linda, I...
It's not that easy, James.
Don't move, asshole!
The rest of you people go back
down to your apartments, now!
I understand you left quite a mess
up there in Big Bear, Mr. Morar.
Duherst, listen.
It's not what you think.
Listen to me. Don't...
Mrs. Brewster, can you stand?
You won't kill her, James.
I'll just shoot her in the leg.
That won't change anything.
It'll buy us some time.
Time to fight you. Time for
Linda to close the portal.
Only you can do that, James.
Put it down.
Put it down!
You're so... smart.
You haven't figured it out
yet, have you, James?
You're the portal.
Not Linda.
You're the one I opened.
You're the one I terrorized
by torturing
Linda and killing your friends.
And it's mine as long as you live.
Bullshit.
Bullshit, you tried to kill me.
No. Just to scare you.
You're the portal, James.
Want to save Linda? That's right.
You've got the means right there in
your hands. Go ahead, James.
Close the portal.
But you won't.
You can't.
You don't love her that much.
Not that much.
Linda.
Is she worth it, James?
Is anybody really worth it?
Think about it.
Jim, don't!
I now pronounce you man and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
Look what I found.
A Ouija board. Gee, I haven't seen
one of these since I was a kid.
I didn't know they've
been around that long.
I wonder if it still works.
With all those holes in it?